翻译，压制：旋火
视频来源：youtu.be/rPks77igQ0I
→  IXV - 掌握大气再入能力
Launching a spacecraft into space is one thing.
启动航天器送入太空是一回事
Bringing it back is another.
带回来是另一回事
Forces such as gravity and drag make atmospheric re-entry a very tricky business.
重力和阻力这样的力 让再入大气层变得非常棘手
But mastering it can open a whole new world of opportunities for Europe.
但掌握这个能力 可以给欧洲开拓一个全新的领域
Re-entry technology is as something that Europa has to master
再入技术是欧洲人必须要攻克的
注：欧空局IXV项目经理
to fulfill the ambition to bring up to completion robotic exploration mission.
这样才能完成一些无人探测任务 这是一直以来的愿景
So for a simple return from asteroids or from Mars
这样 对于小行星和火星的采样返回任务
as well as for human spaceflight
以及载人航天
if one day we'll have the ambition to
未来我们将有信心
have astronauts flying back to earth with the European technologies.
用欧洲的技术将宇航员带回地球
This is precisely the mission of IXV.
这正是IXV的使命
ESA's Intermediate eXperimental Vehicle.
欧空局的过渡试验飞行器
A vehicle with the shape of a 5 meter long shuttle
5米长的梭形载具
weighing some two tons filled and covered with sensors to fulfill its task.
重约2吨 借助遍布表面与内部的传感器来完成其任务
IXV is a technological demonstrator
IXV是一个技术验证机
注：泰雷兹阿莱尼亚宇航公司IXV项目经理
whose purpose is to experiment the technologies associated to the atmosphere re-entry
其目的是试验大气再入相关技术
which is a very challenging task.
这是一个非常具有挑战性的任务
I would say the most challenging tasks among the space business.
是太空业务中最具挑战性的任务
It is something that Europe has never done before with a lifting body with this shape.
升力体形状的航天器是欧洲从未涉足过的领域
注：Vega音译维加
IXV will be launched by Vega, Europe's lightweight rocket, into a suborbital path.
IXV将由欧洲小型运载火箭Vega发射进入亚轨道
After separation, it will fly over the earth to reach the re-entry point
器箭分离后 将在地球上空飞行至再入位置
and begin validating critical atmospheric re-entry technologies
并开始验证重要的再入大气层技术
as it cruises to its final destination.
此时它正飞往目的地
Launched from South America,
从南美洲发射
it will splash down in the middle of the Pacific Ocean less than two hours later.
它会在不到两个小时后于太平洋中间溅落
注：欧空局IXV航电工程师
The first objective is to measure
第一个目标是测量
with the help of more than 300 pressure and temperature sensors,
在超过300个的压力和温度传感器的帮助下
all the phenomenon that will allow us
这些现象会帮助我们
to validate the aero thermo dynamical behavior of the vehicle in hypersonic flight.
验证高超音速飞行过程中载具的空气动力学和热力学表现
The second objective is
第二个目标是
to validate the in-flight performance of all the advanced thermal protections used
验证所有先进的热保护材料在飞行中的性能
which are ceramic and ablative materials.
譬如陶瓷和热烧蚀材料
Having successfully completed the development, qualification and test phases
在成功地完成了开发 认证和测试阶段之后
IXV is now getting ready for launch from Europe's spaceport in Kourou, French Guiana.
IXV现正准备从法属圭亚那库鲁的欧洲太空港 发射升空
With this launch,
有了这次发射
IXV will not only set an important milestone in Europe's path to future autonomous atmospheric re-entry vehicles,
IXV不仅是未来欧洲无人大气再入飞行器研制的一个重要里程碑
it will also be Vega's fourth launch
而且也是Vega火箭的第四次发射
demonstrating all the potential and diversity of the latest European launcher
展示最新的欧洲运载火箭提供的潜力和多样性
for sending all types of payload to many different orbits
代表着各种类型的有效载荷能被发送到各种不同的轨道